Today, in this segment of bar tools, I'm going to discuss the bar spoon.
Now, your bar spoon is a long spoon, it's twisted in the center.
It may or may not have an end, like such.
This is a flat circular end.
There's a lot of uses for this.
Most common, basically stirring your drinks, layering shots or Martinis and scraping out all that ice at the bottom of the blender.
So, really quickly, first use that I explained was stirring your drinks.
When this is filled with ice and all of your contents, you're just going to place the spoon in like that to the bottom, and just stir it.
And what this does, it allows you to prevent bruising your drink.
It's just a different method of mixing your ingredients as opposed to shaking.
The other example that I'm going to show you is layering your drinks.
You're going to want to start with your shot glass, obviously and from that point, you're going to take your first liqueur, this is a Butterscotch Schnapps.
And we're going to pour about halfway up.
From that point, you're going to take your bar spoon and your next, which is going to be Bailey's Irish Creme, and you're going to just want to penetrate the surface of whatever your first or base alcohol is and pour the second one directly on top of the spoon, like such.
And see how it gives you a really nice, distinct, separated layer there.
So, those are the uses of your bar spoon.
Always recommend having this behind the bar and take good care of it.